Previously:
前情提要：
There's this woman that I like a lot.
我很喜歡一個女人
But it's complicated.
事情很複雜
She was with this other guy for a long time.
她跟另一個男人 交往了很久
I could never do that to the guy. We're friends.
我沒辦法那樣對他 我們是好朋友
So this guy she used to go out with, is he a good guy?
以前跟她交往過的那個男人 他是好人嗎？
The best.
他是最棒的
-Then talk to him. -I don't know.
-跟他談一談 -我不知道
It's worth finding out, if you like her.
如果你喜歡她 這值得試一試
I do, so much.
我真的非常喜歡她
I can't stop thinking about her. I can't sleep..
我沒辦法不想到她 我睡不著…
You know what? You have to go for it.
你知道嗎？ 你得盡力去爭取
How often does this happen to you? You owe it to yourself.
你常遇到這種事嗎？ 你應該為自己這麼做的
It's Rachel.
是瑞秋
I'm sorry, did you just say it's Rachel?
對不起 你剛剛說是瑞秋嗎？
Yes.
對
You like Rachel?
你喜歡瑞秋？
Yes. I like Rachel.
對，我喜歡瑞秋
Rachel?!
瑞秋
Yeah. Okay, but look, you know..
對，聽著，你知道的…
You know who else I like? You.
你知道我還喜歡誰嗎？你
And it doesn't get said enough. I like you, Ross.
光說還是不夠的 我喜歡你，羅斯
-"Rachel" Rachel? -It's not a big deal.
-那個「瑞秋」？ -沒什麼大不了的
It's not a big deal? I'm sorry, I just..
沒什麼大不了的？ 抱歉，我只是…
What about the stuff you said?
你剛剛說的那些話呢？
How you can't stop thinking about her? How you can't sleep?
你說你無法不去想她 你說你睡不著
I'm an actor, you know?
我是個演員，你知道嗎？
As a group, we tend to be overdramatic.
演員習慣了誇張
Rachel-who's-carrying-my-baby Rachel?
懷著我孩子的瑞秋？
I know it's bad. And I know it's wrong, okay?
我知道那很糟糕 我知道那是不對的，好嗎？
It's not like anything's ever gonna happen.
那是不可能會發生的事
These are just feelings. They'll go away.
那只是我的感覺 它們會消失的
You know, I gotta go.
我得走了
Hey, Ross..
羅斯
You know, I just have one-- Rachel?!
我只是有個… 瑞秋？
Rachel?!
瑞秋？
The One Where Joey Tells Rachel
本集播出：喬依告訴瑞秋
rainystar壓制iPod-MP4
Okay, she's kicking.
她在踢我
She's growing inside you.
她在你的體內成長
-That was a big one. -That's the youngest girl to reject me.
-這一下踢得好用力 -她是拒絕我的最年輕的女孩
-You guys! -Hey there.
-大家好 -嗨
Let me ask you. Do you believe in soul mates?
我要問你們 你們相信有心靈伴侶嗎？
Oh, yes, I do.
我相信
There's one person out there for everyone.
每個人都有失落的另一半
You know how you find him? Stop looking.
你知道你該怎麼找到他嗎？ 停止再找了
I've stopped looking for Russell Crowe.
我已經停止尋找羅素克洛
He'll find me.
他會找到我的
And you?
你呢？
No. I believe that certain people are more suited for each other, but..
不，我相信有些人 非常適合彼此，但是…
-Soul mates? I don't think they exist. -Good.
-心靈伴侶？我想他們並不存在 -很好
-Why? -Well, last night, I met Monica's.
-為什麼？ -昨晚我遇到了摩妮卡的心靈伴侶
What?
什麼？
I had a date with this guy. I swear he's her other half.
我跟這個男的約會 我發誓他是她的另一半
You don't think there's somebody better suited for Monica than me?
你不覺得會有人 比我更適合摩妮卡吧？
Well, what's he like?
他長什麼樣子？
-He's tall. He has brown hair. -Of course.
-他很高，是棕髮 -當然
A tall guy with hair similar to mine? Oh, unknowable universe!
一個髮色跟我一樣的高大男人？ 宇宙真的是太大了
-He works with food. -Oh, sure. Older?
-他從事跟食物相關的行業 -當然，他比較老嗎？
-Obviously. And he's British. -I was just gonna ask!
-沒錯，他是英國人 -我正打算要問你
And he's so centered, and mature and confident.
他非常聰明 成熟有自信
It's so sad they never met.
真可惜他們不認識彼此
Luckily, the guy she settled for can't hear you.
還好她老公沒聽到你那麼說
Oh, I'm so sorry. Maybe I'm wrong.
抱歉 或許我錯了
We're going out again. I'll find out more.
我們會再約會 我會把他調查得更仔細
He's meant for her, and you're gonna date him?
他跟別人是天生一對 你還要跟他約會？
He may not be my soul mate, but a girl's gotta eat.
或許他不是我的心靈伴侶 但我總得吃飯吧
Rachel?!
瑞秋
I didn't know Joey was on JAG.
我不知道喬伊演過《執法悍將》
-Hey. -Hey.
-嘿 -嘿
I talked to Joey. I wanted to see you.
我剛跟喬伊談過 我想知道你好不好
I still can't believe it. Joey and Rachel?
我還是不敢相信 喬伊跟瑞秋？
It's like you and me going out, only weirder.
那像是你跟我在交往 只不過更奇怪
I know you're hurting..
我知道你很難過 我也想安慰你…
but don't say that again.
但別再那麼說了
What if they marry? He'd be the stepfather of my child.
如果他們結婚了呢？ 他可能是我孩子的繼父
You don't need to worry.
你不必擔心
He'll never tell her how he feels.
他不會告訴她他的感覺
If he did, you don't know how she'd react.
就算他說了 你不知道她會有什麼反應
Sure, women never like Joey. I think he's a virgin.
女人從來就不喜歡喬伊 我想他是個處男
-He isn't thinking about going for her. -He's not?
-他不想追她 -真的嗎？
All he's thinking about is how you're taking this.
他只想到你的感覺
It's freaking him out. He wants to move to Vermont.
這把他嚇壞了 他想搬到佛蒙特去
-Why? -He wants to leave the country.
-為什麼？ -他想離開這個國家
He thinks you hate him.
他認為你恨他
Hate him?
恨他？
No, I don't hate him.
不，我不恨他
It's just, it's Rachel. You know?
她是瑞秋，你知道嗎？
I can't even imagine how hard this must be for you..
我無法想像你有多難過…
but I don't want you to lose Joey over it.
但我不希望你跟喬伊 因此做不成朋友
Right now, he needs to know that you're still his friend.
現在他得知道 你還是他的朋友
Okay, I'll talk to him.
好吧，我會跟他談
I'd do it soon.
你最好快去
He just asked me how to convert his dollars into Vermont money.
他問我怎麼把美金 換成佛蒙特貨幣
-Hi! -Hi.
-嗨 -嗨
-Chandler, Monica, this is Don. -Hello.
-錢德，摩妮卡，他是唐 -哈囉
Hello, nice to meet you. How are you?
哈囉，很高興能認識你 你好嗎？
Soul mate.
心靈伴侶
-What are you guys doing? -We had lunch at Adriatica.
-你們做了什麼？ -我們在艾德瑞提卡吃午餐
-What's with the sun-dried tomatoes? -I know! Is this 1985?
-蕃茄干是怎麼了？ -我知道，它是1985年的嗎？
-That's what I said! Isn't it strange? -Not really.
-我就是那麼說的，這很奇怪吧？ -一點都不會
What's wrong with sun-dried tomatoes?
蕃茄干是怎麼了？
On a barbecued-chicken pizza?
在烤雞披薩上嗎？
No?
不是嗎？
-What restaurants do you like? -Octavio. 27-and-7.
-你喜歡哪家餐廳？ -奧克塔維歐，27與7
-There's this place, Alessandro's. -Oh, my God! I'm the chef!
-還有亞利山多洛斯 -天啊，我是那裡的主廚
You're kidding! Your food is fantastic!
你是在開玩笑 你做的菜好吃極了
I want to talk about your menu. Anyone want coffee?
我要跟你談談你的菜單 有人要喝咖啡嗎？
If you're talking about me, I'll go with you.
我要喝拿鐵，如果你要談我的事 我跟你一起去
I'll have a mocha-ccino.
我要喝摩卡奇諾
What are you doing?
你在做什麼？
I swear, I didn't know you guys would be here.
我發誓我不知道你們在這裡
You don't believe in soul mates, so..
你不相信心靈伴侶，所以…
I believe in handsome strangers who hit on my wife.
我相信英俊的陌生人追我的老婆
Just because I think they're soul mates doesn't mean anything'll happen.
雖然我認為他們是心靈伴侶 那不代表會發生什麼事
Phoebe? Good work.
菲比？ 做的好
He's great. I love him.
他很棒，我愛他
Don't worry, we'll find you someone else.
別擔心 我們會幫你找到對像
I understand if you came by to hit me. I deserve it.
如果你是來打我的，我瞭解 這是我活該
No, I don't want to hit you.
不，我不想打你
What, then? Kick me?
什麼？你要踢我？
No.
不
Bite me?
咬我？
I don't want to do anything to you.
我不想對你怎麼樣
I just want to say I'm not mad at you..
我只是要說 我沒有生你的氣…
and that I certainly do not hate you.
我當然也不恨你
I just came here to say that.
我只是來告訴你
Hey, wait, Ross?
等一下，羅斯
You wanna come in for a beer or something?
你想進來喝瓶啤酒嗎？
Yeah, sure.
好吧
You got any beer?
你有啤酒嗎？
All I got is melon stuff that Rachel left.
我只有瑞秋留下香瓜飲料
Okay.
好吧
You need to understand something.
你得瞭解一件事
I am never gonna act on this Rachel thing, okay?
我不會對瑞秋採取行動，好吧？
I wouldn't do anything to jeopardize my friendship with you.
我不會做出任何 會危及你我友誼的事
Thank you.
謝謝
Anyway, it'll just..
總之我只是…
It'll take me a while to get over her.
我得花點時間去遺忘它
I'm not sure how to do that. I've never been in love, so..
我不確定我該怎麼做 我沒有陷入愛河過，所以…
What?
什麼？
You're in love with her?
你愛上她了？
-Yeah. I thought you knew that. -No.
-對，我以為你知道 -不
Look, if it helps, I don't want to feel this way, honest.
聽著，如果有幫助的話 我真的也不希望自己有那種感覺
I just keep thinking, "I'll get over this, " you know?
我只是一直在想 「我得忘了這件事」，你知道嗎？
But it just keeps getting harder.
但我越這麼想就越忘不了
I don't know what to do, you know?
我不知道該怎麼辦
What do I do?
我該怎麼辦？
-You need to tell her how you feel. -That's the green stuff talking.
-你得告訴她你的感覺 -那一定是飲料害你這麼說的
I'm serious. You need to find out where she is.
我是認真的 你得知道她的感覺
If she's not where you are, you can start to move on.
如果她不喜歡你 你可以繼續往前走
But what if, and I'm not saying she will be..
但如果 我不是說她會…
If she is where you are..
如果她喜歡你…
then my feeling weird shouldn't stand in the way.
我的尷尬感覺不該妨礙你們
-Are you sure? -Yeah.
-你確定？ -對
If she ends up with somebody else..
如果她會跟別的男人在一起…
the truth is, she couldn't find a better guy.
說真的 她找不到更好的人選
Hey, thanks.
謝謝
-So when are you gonna talk to her? -Oh, my God. I have to tell her.
-你什麼時候要跟她談？ -天啊，我得跟她談
I haven't thought about it. What should I say?
我還沒有想過 我該說什麼？
I'm understanding, but let's not get carried away.
我能體諒你 但我們別太過份了
What am I gonna say?
我該說什麼？
Yeah, tell me about it.
你說的對
I'm phasing out the wine importing and focusing more on the cheese.
我解決了進口酒的問題 現在全力研究起司
Cheese, you say?
你說起司嗎？
That's some pretty smelly work, huh, Don?
就是那種臭臭的東西，唐
-Excuse me? -Cheese. It's smelly.
-對不起 -起司很臭
You must smell a lot of the time too.
你一定也常常聞起來很臭
Not really. But with cheese, I think the smellier, the better.
不會的 但我覺得起司越臭越好
Me too! Chandler hates it. I can't have blue cheese in the house.
我也是，錢德討厭它 在家我不能吃藍起司
And you're still married to him?
你還是嫁給了他？
I would like to go to France and eat nothing but bread and cheese.
我想到法國只吃麵包跟起司
Not even bread. Just cheese.
甚至不要麵包，只要起司
No, I want the bread.
不，我要麵包
And pastries.
還有餡餅
And pate.
跟小餡餅
I'm really not high. I just used to be fat.
我不是真的興奮 只是以前我很胖
I have a villa in the Loire Valley you can stay in.
我在羅亞爾谷有棟別墅 你可以住在那裡
Is it made of cheese?
它是用起司做的嗎？
No. A house made of cheese, wouldn't that be incredible?
不，用起司做的房子 那很不可思議吧？
-I'd move in tomorrow! -Oh, come on!
-我明天就想搬進去 -少來了
-Listen to this! -I'm so sorry.
-你聽到了嗎？ -對不起
-What do we do? -They both want a house of cheese.
-我們該怎麼辦？ -他們都要起司屋
I don't know how you fight that.
我不知道你該怎麼辦
Okay, okay. I can do this. I can tell her how I feel.
好吧，我可以這麼做 我可以告訴她我的感覺
Okay, stand up straight.
好吧，挺直腰桿
Take a couple deep breaths.
深呼吸一下
Look confident.
表現出自信
Joey? What's up?
喬伊，怎麼了？
I came by because I want to talk to you about something.
我來找你 因為我想告訴你一件事
What's up?
怎麼了？
Here, in the hall? What are we, animals?
就在走廊上談？ 我們是動物嗎？
I'm late for a meeting. Could you make it quick?
我開會要遲到了 你能快點說嗎？
I just came by to tell you that..
我是來告訴你…
I want to have dinner with you.
我想跟你一起吃晚餐
Sure. Just tell me where to meet you.
沒問題，告訴我到哪裡找你
Okay. That's good.
好吧，太棒了
That gives you a couple of hours to prepare.
這給你 幾小時的時間做好準備
Don't you people ever knock?
你們從來不敲門嗎？
I'd like to have Don and Phoebe over. Wouldn't that be nice?
我想請唐跟菲比過來 那真的很棒吧？
Sure. Set it up.
沒問題，你去安排吧
I'll just be browsing through the personals.
我只是在看找伴分類廣告
Are you okay? You're acting weird.
你沒事吧？ 你有點怪怪的
Yeah. Fine. Not perfect.
好吧，我不完美
But good enough.
但我夠好了
Jeez, what's with you?
天啊，你是怎麼了？
I'm sorry, did you say "cheese"?
抱歉，你剛剛說「起司」嗎？
-What's going on? -Phoebe says you and Don are soul mates.
-怎麼了？ -菲比說你跟唐是心靈伴侶
I don't believe in that, but you two get along.
我不相信 但你們兩個處得很好
I'll step aside if you wanna go with Don and live in a house of cheese.
如果你想跟唐住在起司屋 我可以退出
-You don't believe in soul mates? -No, but I'm sure "tomahtoes" does.
-你不相信心靈伴侶？ -對，但我相信「蕃茄干先生」相信
I don't believe in soul mates, either.
我也不相信心靈伴侶
-You don't? -Nope.
-你不相信？ -對
We weren't destined to end up together.
我們不是注定要在一起的
We fell in love and work hard at our relationship.
我們陷入愛河 努力經營我們的關係
Some days we work really hard.
有時候我們非常努力
So you don't want to live with Don in a cheese house?
你不想跟唐住在起司屋？
No, I've had second thoughts. Do you know how hard it'd be to clean?
不，我想了一下 你知道它打掃起來有多辛苦嗎？
-I love you. -I know.
-我愛你 -我知道
I'm gonna take you out to dinner.
我要帶你去吃晚餐
I found this place that makes the greatest jalapeno poppers.
我找到一個 做墨西哥辣椒卷最好吃的地方
No? They taste so good.
不？它們真的很好吃
It happens whenever Chandler touches my stomach.
錢德一摸我的肚子就會這樣
I'm worried the baby won't like him.
我擔心寶寶不喜歡他
-Are you okay? -Yeah, sure.
-你沒事吧？ -沒事
Look, the reason..
聽著，我…
Is it hot in here?
這裡很熱嗎？
Why don't you take off your sweater?
你為什麼不把毛衣脫掉？
This is a nice place..
這個地方不錯…
and my T-shirt has a picture of Calvin doing Hobbes.
我的T恤印了 卡爾文上荷比絲的樣子
Oh, my God, really? Can I see it?
天啊，真的嗎？我能看一下嗎？
Yeah, sure.
當然可以
I wouldn't think Hobbes would like that so much.
我想荷比絲不會太喜歡
How long have we known each other?
我們認識多久了？
Seven, eight..
七，八…
Eight years. Wow.
八年了
A long time.
真的很久了
But over the past few weeks, I..
但過去幾星期以來我…
Okay! Sorry about the wait, but it is mega-jammed in here.
好吧，抱歉讓你們久等 今天客人真的很多
Our specials tonight..
今晚的特餐是…
-Could you give us a second? -Sure.
-你能等一下再來嗎？ -好吧
Second's up!
時間到
Not that kind of table.
你們不是那種客人
So you were saying?
你要說什麼？
I'm not sure.
我不確定
You asked how long we knew each other, and I said eight years.
你問我們認識了多久 我說八年
Then the waiter came over and cut his tip in half..
後來服務生走過來 害他少了一半的小費…
and now here we are.
我們說到那裡了
Yeah. Here we are.
沒錯
I think I'm falling in love with you.
我想我愛上你了
What?
什麼？
I'm falling in love with you.
我愛上你了
Who are you talking to?
你在跟誰說話？
Oh, you're kidding. It's a joke.
你在開玩笑，這是鬧著玩的
Funny. It's funny!
真的很好笑
I don't get it.
我不瞭解
Okay.
好吧
Wow.
哇
Okay, so the specials are..
今天的特餐是…
Are you..?
你…
How did..?
怎麼會…
When?
什麼時候？
Does it really matter?
那真的重要嗎？
Wow. Wow.
哇
It is hot in here.
這裡好熱
I know this is a lot.
我知道這真的很令人吃驚
You don't have to say anything.
你什麼都不必說
You take as much time as you need.
你要花多少時間思考都可以
Okay, you gotta say something.
好吧，你得說說話
Joey, I love you so much.
喬伊，我非常愛你
-But.. -But.
-但是… -但是
Joey?
喬伊
Right. Hey, that's..
對，那是…
That's okay. That's fine.
沒關係，真的
It's pretty much what I was expecting.
我料到你會這樣
It's no big deal, all right?
那沒什麼大不了的，好嗎？
-I think I'm gonna go. -Please don't leave like this.
-我想我得走了 -請不要這樣離開
You can't do this to a pregnant woman!
你不能這樣對一個孕婦
Don't start doing that.
別那麼做
You can't do that, because you're gonna make me..
你不能那麼做 因為你把我弄哭了…
Oh, there we go!
我們一起哭吧
-Can I? -Sure.
-可以嗎？ -沒問題
Oh, Joey. I don't want to lose..
喬伊，我不想失去…
Hey, hey.
嘿
You can't, okay? Ever.
你不會的，好嗎？永遠不會
I'm so sorry.
我真的很抱歉
Please don't be sorry.
請你不要那麼說
Okay? Don't be sorry.
好吧？別感到抱歉
You know, I was only kidding.
我只是在開玩笑
Yeah, that was a real good one.
對，那真的很好笑
-Is this your table? -Yeah.
-他們是你的客人？ -對
-You'll be here all night. -I know.
-你得在這裡待上一整晚 -我知道
I haven't even read the specials.
我連特餐內容都還沒有說
What's the matter?
怎麼了？
I don't know. I think maybe one of them is dying.
我不知道 我想或許他們之中有人快死了
I kind of hope it's the girl.
我希望是那個女的
The guy is really cute!
那個男的真的很帥